Guide to the Gail and Stephen Rudin slavery collection, 1728-1973.
Rudin (Gail and Stephen) Slavery Collection,
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Gail and Stephen Rudin slavery collection, 1728-1973.
4681
Stephen, Rudin
5.2 Cubic Feet.
Newspaper engravings, estate appraisals, wills, legal documents, manumissions, correspondence, sheet music, slave taxation records, stereoviews, newspapers
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
The Gail and Stephen Rudin Slavery Collection consists of newspaper engravings, estate appraisals, wills, legal documents, manumissions, reward for capture of runaway slave advertisements, slave dealer and slave trade manuscripts, correspondence, sheet music, slave taxation records, stereoviews and other records documenting the sale, hire, purchase and debt payment of slaves in 18th and 19th century America.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
The Gail and Stephen Rudin Slavery Collection consists of newspaper engravings, estate appraisals, wills, legal documents, manumissions, reward for capture of runaway slave advertisements, slave dealer and slave trade manuscripts, correspondence, sheet music, slave taxation records, stereoviews and other records documenting the sale, hire, purchase and debt payment of slaves in 18th and 19th century America.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Rudin, Stephen,; Clark, Lewis George.; Clay, Henry, 1777-1852.; Johnson, Andrew, 1808-1875.; Rudin,Gail,; Stowe, Harriet Beecher, 1811-1896--Uncle Tom's cabin.; Wayne, Anthony, 1745-1796.; American Colonization Society.; Freedman's Bureau.; United States, Bureau of Refugees, Freedmen, and Abandoned Lands.
Titles:
Harper's Weekly.
Subjects:
Paper money--Confederate States of America.; Abolitionists--United States.; Slavery--United States.; Slavery--United States--History.; African-Americans--History--To 1863.; Slave bills of sale.; Slaveholders.; Slave narratives.; Slave traders.; Fugitive slaves.; Slave trade.; Impressment.; Slavery--Taxation.
Places:
United States--History--Civil War, 1861-1865--Participation, African American.; Southern States.
Form and Genre Terms:
Bills of sale.; Appraisals.; Stereoscopic photographs.; Sheet music.; Legal documents.; Engravings.; Wills.; Free papers.; Insurance policies.; Newspapers.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
SERIES LIST
Series I: Currency
Series II: Engravings, Prints and Lithographs
Series III: Estates, Appraisals, Wills
Series IV: Freedman's Documents
Series V: General Orders
Series VI: Letters
Series VII: Manumissions
Series VIII: Maps
Series IX: Miscellaneous
Series X: Music
Series XI: Newspapers
Series XII: Officers' Pay Vouchers
Series XIII: Pamphlets and Printed Documents
Series XIV: Patriotic Covers
Series XV: Runaway Slave Documents
Series XVI: Sale, Hire, Purchase, Collateral Documents and Slave Codes
Series XVII: Slave Dealers, Slave Trading
Series XVIII: Slave Taxation
Series XIX: Stereoviews and Photographs
Series XX: Objects
CONTAINER LIST
- Series I: Currency
  - $2.00 proof - Vignette of Oxen Pulling Wagon, 18--; Location: Freehold, New Jersey (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Rudin # S - 941
  - $1.00 Note - Slaves gathering turpentine, slaves carrying cotton, 1861; Location: Savannah, Georgia (Box 1, Folder 2)
    Rudin # S - 879
  - $10 Note - Vignette of Negro Picking Cotton, 1861; Location: Richmond, Virginia (Box 1, Folder 2a)
    Rudin # S - 939
  - 50 Cent note - Picture of Fort Sumter, March, 1861; Location: Charleston, South Carolina (Box 1, Folder 3)
    Rudin # S - 725
  - $50.00 Note - Slave gathering corn, March, 1861; Location: Howardsville, Virginia (Box 1, Folder 4)
    Rudin # S - 880
  - $5.00 Note - Slave with Oxen Hauling Cotton, April 4, 1861; Location: Charleston, South Carolina (Box 1, Folder 5)
    Rudin # S - 508
  - 25 Cent Note - Fort Sumter on Fire, April 13, 1861; Location: South Carolina (Box 1, Folder 6)
    Rudin # S - 659
  - $1.00 Note - Slaves Unloading Cotton at Dock From Wagon, May 29, 1861; Location: South Carolina (Box 1, Folder 7)
    Rudin # S - 509
  - $10 Note- Slave Picking Cotton, September 2, 1861; Location: Richmond, Virginia (Box 1, Folder 8)
    Rudin # S - 720
  - $100 Note - Slaves loading cotton wagon, September 2, 1861; Location: Richmond, Virginia (Box 1, Folder 9)
    Rudin # S - 824
  - $50 Note - Slaves picking and carrying cotton, January 1, 1862; Location: Tallahassee, Florida (Box 1, Folder 10)
    Rudin # S - 825
  - $3.00 Note - Maid and Cotton, January 4, 1862; Location: Tennessee (Box 1, Folder 11)
    Rudin # S - 622
  - $20 Note - Slave driving cotton wagon, January 24, 1862; Location: Jackson, Mississippi (Box 1, Folder 12)
    Rudin # S - 827
  - $50 Note - Horse pulling cotton, slave picking cotton, February 7, 1862; Location: Jackson, Mississippi (Box 1, Folder 13)
    Rudin # S - 826
  - $10 Treasury Note - Slave with Two Horses, February 7, 1862; Location: Jackson, Mississippi (Box 1, Folder 14)
    Rudin # S - 923
  - $2.00 Note - Cotton bales, April 15, 1862; Location: Parish of Concordia, Louisiana (Box 1, Folder 15)
    Rudin # S - 940
  - $3.00 Note - Cotton Pledged, May 1, 1862; Location: Mississippi (Box 1, Folder 16)
    Rudin # S - 440
  - $1.00 Note - Overseer and slaves, slaves carrying cotton, slave and a cotton gin, May 1, 1862; Location: Macon, Georgia (Box 1, Folder 17)
    Rudin # S - 897
  - Seven Confederate Bank Notes, ca. 1863; Location: Various (Box 1, Folder 18)
    Rudin # S - 783
  - 5 Cent Note - Cotton Bolls, January 1, 1863; Location: Alabama (Box 1, Folder 19)
    Rudin # S - 506
  - 25 Cent Note - Wagon with Cotton Vignette, January 1, 1863; Location: Alabama (Box 1, Folder 20)
    Rudin # S - 538
  - Scorched $20 Note - Salvaged from the Burning of Atlanta, April 6, 1863; Location: Richmond (Box 1, Folder 21)
    Rudin # S - 869
  - 25 Cent Note - Cotton Bolls, May 1, 1864; Location: Mississippi (Box 1, Folder 22)
    Rudin # S - 550
  - $10 Note - Slave carrying cotton, March 21, 1865; Location: Arkansas (Box 1, Folder 23)
    Rudin # S - 721
  - $1 Note - Cotton wagon drawn by two horses, May 1, 1875; Location: Nashville, Tennessee (Box 1, Folder 24)
    Rudin # S - 924
  - 11 different bank notes, 1860-1864; Location: Mississippi, Alabama, North Carolina, Tennessee, Virginia (Box 1, Folder 25)
    Rudin # S - 77a, b, c, d; 88a, b, c; 99a, b, c, d (11 items)
- Series II: Engravings, Prints and Lithographs
  - "Baumwolle"--depiction of slaves in a cotton field, Location: Leipzig, Germany Format: Chromolithograph (Mapcase-folder 6)
    Rudin # S - 779
  - Print of Slave Sale, Charleston South Carolina. Illustrated London News, Location: London Format: Print (Folder 5)
    Rudin # S - 681
  - Graphite Elastic Paint advertising poster, depicting African American stereotypes, Format: Poster (Folder 3)
    Rudin # S - 974
  - Reconstruction period print satirizes African American, Format: Print (Box 16, Folder 1)
    Rudin # S - 684
  - Copperplate Engraving of the Early African Slave Trade, ca. 1650; Location: Africa Format: Engraving (Box 1, Folder 26)
    Rudin # S - 357
  - Slave Ship Engraving - Engraving of a Ship Showing how many Slaves are Loaded as "Cargo", 1808; Location: W.J. Morgan and Co.; Format: Engraving (Box 21, Folder 7)
    Rudin # S - 423
  - Slave Trade Engraving, 1830; Format: Engraving (Box 1, Folder 27)
    Rudin # S - 226
  - Print showing fashionable white audience listening to a group of black singers, 1840; Location: London Format: Color Lithograph (Box 21, Folder 1)
    Rudin # S - 944
  - Print Burning the Brand into a Slave, ca. 1850; Format: Engraving (Box 1, Folder 28)
    Rudin # S - 267
  - "The Last Daughter," a small slave auction, 1850s; Format: Engraving (Box 1, Folder 29)
    Rudin # S - 882
  - "The Successful Man Hunt," three captured runaway slaves, 1850s; Format: Engraving (Box 1, Folder 30)
    Rudin # S - 883
  - Harpers Weekly Engraving, "The Africans of the Slave Bark Wildfire", 1861 (Box 25, Folder 2)
    Rudin # S - 127
  - Illustrated London News Woodcut, "A Slave Auction in Virginia", 1861 (Box 25, Folder 2)
    Rudin # S - 135
  - Harpers Weekly Engraving, "American Home Scenes", 1861 (Box 25, Folder 3)
    Rudin # S - 128
  - Harpers Weekly Engraving, "A Slave Auction at the South", 1861 (Box 25, Folder 3)
    Rudin # S - 134
  - Harpers Weekly Engraving, "Work's Over", 1861 (Box 25, Folder 3)
    Rudin # S - 131
  - Harpers Weekly Engraving, "Negroes Driven South by Rebel Officers;", 1862 (Box 25, Folder 4)
    Rudin # S - 130
  - "Slavery And Its Consequences" - Two Engravings on One Sheet, 1862; Format: Engravings (Box 1, Folder 31)
    Rudin # S - 301
  - Harpers Weekly Engraving, "The Emancipation of Negroes", 1863 (Box 25, Folder 4)
    Rudin # S - 124
  - Harpers Weekly Engraving, "The Effects of the Proclamation" (Box 25, Folder 4)
    Rudin # S - 132
  - Harpers Weekly, "A Negro Regiment in Action, Liberating Slaves in N. Carolina", 1863 (Box 25, Folder 5)
    Rudin # S - 126
  - Harpers Weekly, "Scenes on a Cotton Plantation", 1864 (Box 25, Folder 5)
    Rudin # S - 133
  - Harpers Weekly, "Southern Justice", 1867 (Box 25, Folder 5)
    Rudin # S - 123
  - Harpers Weekly, "He Wants a Change Too", 1876 (Box 25, Folder 5)
    Rudin # S - 125
  - Lithograph for "Uncle Tom's Cabin", ca. 1880; Location: Cleveland, Ohio Format: Lithograph (Folder 2)
    Rudin # S - 424
  - six hand-colored equestrian prints, 1880s-1890s; Location: New York Format: Color Lithograph (Box 21, Folder 2)
    Rudin # S - 784
  - Fourteen prints from the Darktown Fire Brigade or Hook and Ladder Series, 1880s-1890s; Location: New York Format: Color Lithograph (Box 21, Folder 3)
    Rudin # S - 943
  - Two prints, Billiards from the Darktown Series, 1882; Location: New York Format: Color Lithograph (Box 21, Folder 1)
    Rudin # S - 633
  - "The Darktown Slide. Golly! Am dere an Erfquake?", 1884; Format: Hand-colored Print (Box 21, Folder 8)
    Rudin # S - 1045
  - "The Darktown Hook and Ladder Corps. in Action", 1884; Location: New York Format: Color Lithograph (Box 21, Folder 2)
    Rudin # S - 754
  - "A Literary Debate in the Darktown Club", 1885; Location: New York Format: Color Lithograph (Box 21, Folder 2)
    Rudin # S - 755
  - Two Color lithographs from the Darktown Series: The Darktown Fire Brigade - A Prize Squirt, 1885; Format: Color Lithograph (Box 21, Folder 3)
    Rudin # S - 542
  - Two Color Lithographs from the Darktown Series: Lawn Tennis at Darktown - A Scientific Stroke Lawn Tennis at Darktown - A Scientific Player, 1885; Location: New York Format: Color Lithograph (Box 21, Folder 3)
    Rudin # S - 553
  - "The Last Hit of the Game. A Home Run", 1886; Format: Hand-colored Print (Box 21, Folder 8)
    Rudin # S - 1046
  - Two Color Lithographs from the Darktown Series: The Darktown Fire Brigade - Under Full Steam Darktown Sports - A Grand Spurt, 1887; Location: New York Format: Color Lithograph (Box 21, Folder 4)
    Rudin # S - 552
  - Two Color Lithographs from the Darktown Series: Trial by Jury - The Verdict A Darktown Trial - The Judge's Charge, 1887; Location: New York Format: Color Lithograph (Box 21, Folder 4)
    Rudin # S - 554
  - From American Bondage to the Halls of Congress. Lincoln surrounded by 18 vignettes depicting life after slavery., 1897; Format: Chromolithograph (Mapcase-folder 6)
    Rudin # S - 674
  - Chromolithograph image of 2 children, with note and certificate for Mary Pearl Chance, ca. 1899; Format: Lithograph (Box 16, Folder 2)
    Rudin # S - 801
  - Full color poster, "Picking Cotton by Hand in the USA", ca. 1940; Format: Poster (Box 21, Folder 4)
    Rudin # S - 799
- Series III: Estates, Appraisals and Wills
  - Thomas Falconer cotton plantation account book, with journal of slave financial accounts and family records, Location: Silver Lake Plantation, Wayne County, Mississippi (Box 34)
    Rudin # S - 935
  - Last Will and Testament Emancipating Slaves after Owner's Death, Location: Calvert County, MD Format: MDoc (Box 1, Folder 32)
    Rudin # S - 382
  - List of personal assets of Harvey Wheats estate, including slave mother and child, Format: MDoc (Box 40, Folder 1)
    Rudin # S - 648
  - Last Will and Testament of Lionell Brittin, including the manumission of his two slaves, January 20, 1721; Location: Philadelphia, Pennsylvania Format: MDocS (Box 16, Folder 3)
    Rudin # S - 926
  - Luther and Eliphalet Leonard estate inventory, includes a Slave appraised along with cow hides, cattle and pigs all to be given to heirs, Circa February 22, 1762; Location: Massachusetts Format: DocS (Box 16, Folder 3a)
    Rudin # S - 600
  - Inventory of a Slave-Holding Plantation, August 15, 1805; Location: Saint Mary's County, Maryland Format: MDocS (Box 41, Folder 1)
  - Inventory of a Slave-Holding Plantation, August 15, 1805; Location: Saint Mary's County, Maryland Format: MDocS (Box 41, Folder 1)
    Rudin # S - 441
  - Georgia Plantation Account Sheet, 1807; Location: Chatham County, Georgia Format: MDOC (Box 21, Folder 5)
    Rudin # S - 426
  - Estate Appraisal Listing Two Female Slaves, November 2, 1813; Location: Garrard County Court, Kentucky Format: MDocS (Box 40, Folder 2)
    Rudin # S - 312
  - Estate list of Wm. Byars, 1815; Location: Virginia Format: MDOC (Box 1, Folder 33)
    Rudin # S - 145
  - Inventory of the goods, chattel and personal estate of Colonel John Simpson, including slaves, October 15, 1815; Location: Laurens County, South Carolina Format: MDocS (Box 16, Folder 4)
    Rudin # S - 928
  - Kentucky Estate Sale, 1821; Location: Kentucky Format: MDOC (Box 1, Folder 34)
    Rudin # S - 108
  - Division of Slaves in the Estate of Bennett Ferrell, ca. 1830; Location: Format: MDocS (Box 40, Folder 3)
    Rudin # S - 236
  - Abel Brewster, last will and testament bequeaths portion of the estate to the American Colonization Society, December 4, 1831; Location: Hartford, Connecticut Format: MDocS (Box 1, Folder 35)
    Rudin # S - 601
  - Martin Green's Will, ordering that his slaves be liberated, December 1, 1832; Location: Madison, Kentucky Format: MDocS (Box 40, Folder 4)
    Rudin # S - 901
  - Last Will and Testament of William Rowland leaving slaves to family members, December 22, 1833; Location: Virginia Format: MDOC (Box 1, Folder 36)
    Rudin # S - 3
  - Sugar plantation record book, containing a list of work and people needed to keep facilities running. William Walsh, 1935-1973; Location: Parc Perdu Plantation, St Martin Parish, Louisiana Format: Book (Box 35)
    Rudin # S - 973
  - Will of Justus Hartman of, freeing his slaves, 1839; Location: South Carolina (Box 16, Folder 22)
    Rudin # S - 17
  - Will that frees slaves after the crops are harvested, September 2, 1839; Location: Kentucky Format: MDocS (Box 40, Folder 5)
    Rudin # S - 167
  - Account of the Hiring of Slaves of the Estate of Wiley Jones, January 11, 1841; Location: Court of Wilcox County, Alabama Format: MDocS (Box 40, Folder 6)
    Rudin # S - 460
  - Stephen Goggin, last will and testament emancipating slaves and leaving them the estate, March 24, 1841; Location: Madison County, Kentucky Format: MDocS (Box 40, Folder 7)
    Rudin # S -840
  - Sale Ledger for Lindsay Estate, June 17, 1843; Location: Bourbon County, Kentucky Format: MDocS (Box 16, Folder 5)
    Rudin # S - 173
  - Accounting of Estate Expenses - deals with shipping cotton to Glasgow, 1843-1846; Location: Alabama Format: MDocS (Box 16, Folder 6)
    Rudin # S - 281
  - Magnolia Forest Slave Plantation Account Book, 1844-1846; Location: Louisiana Format: MDocS (Box 1, Folder 37)
    Rudin # S -176
  - Free Man of Color Writes his Last Will and Testament, October 14, 1846; Location: Madison County, KY Format: MDocS (Box 40, Folder 8)
    Rudin # S - 215
  - Sale Bill of the Estate of Silas Hill Including 45 Slaves as well as Tools, Animals and Land, January 12-13, 1847; Location: Newberry District, SC; Format: MDOC (Box 16, Folder 7)
    Rudin # S - 358
  - Will allows slaves to choose their next master, signed John Arnold, August 23, 1847; Location: Bourbon County, Kentucky Format: MDocS (Box 16, Folder 8)
    Rudin # S - 881
  - Division of slaves belonging to Hamilton R. Heath, January 1, 1848; Location: Lee County, Georgia (?) Format: MMDocS (Box 1, Folder 38)
    Rudin # S - 614
  - Will Emancipating Slaves only if they go to Liberia, April 21, 1849; Location: Tennessee Format: MDocS (Box 1, Folder 39)
    Rudin # S - 118
  - Document settling an estate listing human property alongside cattle, wagons, mares, etc., August 29, 1849; Location: Union District, South Carolina Format: MDocS (Box 1, Folder 40)
    Rudin # S - 422
  - Sale of land and slaves ad receipt, Will listing slaves by name in an inheritance (James Bane), October 30, 1849; April 1830; January 1835; Location: Georgia, Virginia Format: MDocS (Box 40, Folder 9)
    Rudin # S - 948
  - Estate Sale Notice, January 4, 1851; Location: Format: MDocS (Box 1, Folder 41)
    Rudin # S - 146
  - Inventory and appraisal of an estate listing slaves and household items with values, February 4, 1853; Location: Wilcox County, Alabama Format: MDocS (Box 16, Folder 9)
    Rudin # S - 743
  - Estate Appraisal including 28 slaves, January 21, 1854; Location: Florida (Box 16, Folder 10)
    Rudin # S - 15
  - Sales Log of the Estate of Edward Wetherford, including list of buyers of slaves, December 27, 1854 and January 29, 1855; Format: MDOC (Box 40, Folder 10)
    Rudin # S - 456
  - List of Estate Auction Results, January 1, 1856; Location: Georgia (Box 16, Folder 11)
    Rudin # S - 37
  - Will of Martin Kolb bequeathing named slaves to his children and grandchildren, January 21, 1856; June 1, 1857; Location: Campbell County, Georgia Format: MDocS (Box 16, Folder 12)
    Rudin # S - 861
  - Property Levy including 154 slaves by name, July 29, 1856; Location: Alabama (Box 16, Folder 13)
    Rudin # S - 27
  - Document listing the division of 59 slaves, December 10, 1857; Location: Tennessee (Box 16, Folder 14)
    Rudin # S - 101
  - Estate appraisal including 100 year-old slave, plus letter to judge and letter from executor, August-December, 1859; Location: Mississippi Format: MDocS (Box 16, Folder 15)
    Rudin # S - 617
  - Accounting of Large Estate of Thomas Riviere, Including the Hiring Out of 31 Named Slaves, December 13-14, 1859; Location: Upson County, Georgia Format: MDoc (Box 16, Folder 16)
    Rudin # S - 368
  - Last Will and Testament Leaves Slaves to Daughter, February 6, 1860; Location: Hinds County, Missouri Format: MDocS (Box 40, Folder 11)
    Rudin # S - 360
  - List of estate of Henry Sanders, including 26 slaves with names, September 5, 1860; Location: Greensburg, Kentucky Format: MDocS (Box 16, Folder 17)
    Rudin # S - 864
  - Newspaper Clipping; Will of Hannah Robinson Including Instructions Regarding her Slaves, November 6-December 17, 1861; Location: Union District, South Carolina Format: MDocS (Box 16, Folder 18)
    Rudin # S - 359
  - Last Will and Testament of John Stalnaker making special arrangements for the payment and freedom of two slaves, July 7, 1862; Location: Randolph County, Virginia Format: MDocS (Box 16, Folder 19)
    Rudin # S - 499
  - Estate Inventory Written on Verso of Confederate Cotton Loan, September 5, 1862; Location: Alabama Format: MDocS (Box 16, Folder 20)
    Rudin # S - 329
  - Last will and testament of Joseph Cooper, with 1864 Probate decision, dividing slaves among his children and allowing some slaves to choose, September 9, 1862; 1864; Location: Hinds County, Mississippi Format: MDocS (Box 1, Folder 42)
    Rudin # S - 930
  - Appraisal of 38 slaves for use in defense of Richmond, November 6 and 11, 1862; Location: Richmond, Virginia Format: MDocS (Box 1, Folder 43)
    Rudin # S - 638
  - Receipt Listing Eight Slaves who were Owned by the Estate of John Branch, former Governor of both Florida and North Carolina, April 28, 1863; Location: Enfield, NC Format: MDocS (Box 1, Folder 44)
    Rudin # S - 570
  - Hand written estate inventory of John Kinder, with 51 slaves listed, October 19, 1863; Format: MDocS (Box 16, Folder 21)
    Rudin # S - 894
- Series IV: Freedmen's Documents
  - Freedman Circular Asking Freedmen to Observe August 6, 1863 as a Day of Public Thanksgiving. Two copies, Location: Beaufort, South Carolina Format: Ptd Circular (Box 2, Folder 1)
    Rudin # S - 531, S - 575
  - Minister Informs Authorities of a Freeman, June 5, 1750; Location: Cambridge, New Hampshire Format: ALS (Box 2, Folder 2)
    Rudin # S - 443
  - "Free Person of Color" Passports, July 4, 1838; May 23, 1840; April 17, 1854; Location: Rockingham County, Harrisonberg Virginia, Courtland Alabama Format: MDocS (Box 2, Folder 3)
    Rudin # S - 447
  - Freed Slaves are Relocated in Africa- American Colonization Society request, December 13, 1849; Location: Indianapolis Format: Ptd DOC (Box 2, Folder 4)
    Rudin # S - 207
  - Declaration of Freedman Status, June 5, 1851; Location: King George County, Virginia Format: MDocS (Box 2, Folder 5)
    Rudin # S - 286
  - Thomas Allen Tidball freeman's court document of William Sibert, a man of color, attesting to the fact that he was born free., August 6, 1855; Location: Frederick County, Virginia Format: DocS (Box 2, Folder 5a)
    Rudin # S - 831
  - "United States Primer" - textbook written expressly for Freedmen and Freedwomen, 1864; Location: American Tract Society, New York Format: Book (Box 2, Folder 6)
    Rudin # S - 637
  - "A Happy New Years Greeting" - Freedmen circular, January 1, 1864; Location: Beaufort, South Carolina Format: Ptd Doc, signed in type (Box 2, Folder 7)
    Rudin # S - 741
  - Speech of Hon. Charles Sumner on the bill to establish a bureau of Freedmen, June 13, 15, 1864; Location: Washington, DC Format: Ptd Doc (Box 2, Folder 8)
    Rudin # S - 865
  - Letter to Asst. Provost Marshal of Freedmen, "West of Natchez," from Col. Thomas, September 9, 1864; Location: Vicksburg, Mississippi Format: MDocS (Box 2, Folder 9)
    Rudin # S - 61
  - Letter signed by John Eaton, Jr. as Colonel and General Superintendent of Freedmen, October 14, 1864; Location: Tennessee Format: TLS (Box 2, Folder 10)
    Rudin # S - 62
  - Letter about tending to the freedmen by the hundreds, November 28, 1864; Format: ALS Writer: Philip W. Waggoner Writer's location: Columbus, Kentucky Addressee:Captain Walker (Box 2, Folder 11)
    Rudin # S - 652
  - Payroll of black "freed laborers" for a month's work on President's Island, 1865; Format: MDS (Box 2, Folder 11A)
    Rudin # S - 1037
  - Rent of School House by Freeman's Bureau, January 10, 1865; Format: Ptd DOC (Box 2, Folder 12)
    Rudin # S - 21
  - Freedman's Document Signed by John Eaton, regarding distributing Army stockings, February, 1865; Location: Tennessee Format: (Box 2, Folder 13)
    Rudin # S - 60
  - Rent of School House by Freeman's Bureau, April 22, 1865; Location: Memphis, Tennessee Format: Ptd DOC (Box 2, Folder 14)
    Rudin # S - 530
  - General Order #91, Organizing Bureau of Refugees, Freedmen and Abandoned Lands, May 12, 1865; Location: Washington, DC Format: Ptd Doc (Box 2, Folder 15)
    Rudin # S - 95
  - Special Orders No. 14 pertaining to property requests for the bureau of refugees and freedmen, July 3, 1865; Location: Richmond, Virginia Format: MDocS (Box 2, Folder 16)
    Rudin # S - 846
  - Freedman Amendment - President Johnson's objections, ca. 1865; Location: Washington, DC (Box 2, Folder 17)
    Rudin # S - 69
  - Rations for Freedmen in the Former Confederate States, July 9, 1866; Location: Washington City Format: Ptd Doc (Box 2, Folder 18)
    Rudin # S - 571
  - Letter on Women's Freedmen's Relief Association Stationary Regarding What Can Be Done to Aid the Freedmen, November 28, 1866; Location: Philadelphia, PA Format: ALS (Box 2, Folder 19)
    Rudin # S - 535